Sokidon Proudly Presents
双语合并：叉烧土豆瘦肉饭
片名  金刚
$ 我正坐在世界的顶端
# I'n sittir on top
of the world #
$ 我在摇摆
# I'n rollir along #
$ 是的，在摇摆
# Yes, rollir along #
$ 我正退离尘世的阴霾
# And I'n quittir
the blues of the world #
$ 我唱着一首歌
# I'n singir a song #
$ 是的，唱一首歌
# Yes, singir a song #
$ 多美妙，哈里路亚！
我曾跟牧师说
# Glory hallelujah!
I just told the parson #
$ “嘿，牧师，是时候召唤了”
# "Hey, Par,
get ready to call" #
$ 就像蛋人那样
# Just like Hunpty Dunpty #
$ 我要摔跟头了
# I'n gonna fall #
$ 我坐在世界的顶端
# And I'n sittir
on top of the world #
$ 我在摇摆
# I'n rollir along #
$ 在摇摆
# Rollir along #
$ 不想要个几百万
# Don't want any nillions #
$ 我有自己的财产
# I'n gettir ny share #
$ 我只有一套西装
就一套
# I've only got one suit
just one #
走啊
Move along.
$ 这是我所有能穿的
# That's all I can wear #
$ 一捆钞票
# A bundle of noney #
$ 不会让我感到快乐
# Don't nake ne feel gay #
$ 一点甜甜的蜂蜜
# A sweet little honey #
$ 就可以让我说
# Is naking ne say #
$ 我正坐在，坐在世界的顶端
# And I'n sittir, sittir
on top, top of the world #
$ 我在摇摆
# I'n rollir along #
$ 在摇摆
# Rollir along #
$ 我正退离，退离尘世的阴霾
# And I'n quittir
quittir the blues
blues of the world #
$ 我唱着一首歌
# I'n singir a song #
$ 是的，唱一首歌
# Yes, singir a song #
$ 多美妙，哈里路亚！
我曾跟牧师说
# Glory hallelujah!
I just told the parson #
$ “嘿，牧师，是时候召唤了”
# "Hey, Par,
get ready to call" #
$ 就像蛋人那样
# Just like Hunpty Dunpty #
$ 我要摔跟头了
# I'n gonna fall #
$ 是啊！我正坐在世界的顶端
# Yeah! I'n sittir
on top, top of the world #
哦！
Oh!
$ 我在摇摆
# I'n rollir along #
$ 在摇摆
# Rollir along ##
这个喷嚏挺滑稽
是不是比以前的滑稽一些？
That's a funny one.
Isn't that funnier?
令人捧腹，曼尼
It's hysterical, Manny.
只要我们还在笑…
As long as we're laughing...
…就不会为了票房而哭
we won't cry
over the box office.
说到沮丧
Talk about depressing.
20个姑娘头顶羽毛冠
象马戏团的小马一样昂首阔步
Twenty girls in feather boas
prancing around
like circus ponies.
那才真叫令人沮丧呢
That's depressing.
我喜欢好的合唱团
I love a good chorus line.
（《隔绝》  杰克・德里斯库著）
- 这是什么？
- 是出话剧
What's this?
It's a play.
谁写的，安妮？
Who wrote it, Annie?
一个叫德莱斯库的
Some guy. Driscoll.
德莱斯库
Driscoll.
联邦剧院的
From the Federal Theatre.
别太挑剔了，亲爱的
至少还有观众看他们的戏
Don't knock it, honey.
At least they got
an audience.
会好起来的，不是吗，曼尼？
It'll pick up.
Isn't that right, Manny?
总是会好起来的
It always does.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
窍门是从喉咙后部开始酝酿
The trick is to
start to build right from
the back of your throat.
从鼻子打出来也挺不错
Works well
out through the nose, too.
你今天吃东西了吗？
Have you eaten today?
哦…
Oh...
我不是很饿，不用担心我
I'm not hungry.
Don't worry about me.
嘿
Hey.
我现在只有你了
You're all I've got.
来吧，带我去吃晚饭
Come on, take me to dinner.
好吧
Okay.
第三街上的餐厅现在还没关门吧？
You think the kitchen
will still be open
on Third?
汤和饼干，太好了
Soup and biscuits.
Perfect.
（剧院无限期关闭
等候进一步通知）
（安・丹劳 哈里・汉克尔 联合出演
《公园漫步》 现已取消）
哈里，这是怎么回事？
Harry, what's going on?
- 嘿，开门，我们在这里上班
- 不用再来了，女士
Hey, open up! We work here.
Not anymore, lady.
对你来说是没什么
可是我们两个星期没发工资了
It's all right for you.
We haven't had a paycheck
in two weeks.
我们拿什么去吃饭？
How we gonna eat?
- 他们不能就这么跑了！
- 他们已经跑了
They're not getting away
with this!
They just did.
安，没用的
Ann, it's no use.
演出完了，结束了，完结了
The show, it's over.
It's done.
我也完结了
I'm done.
我要走了，安妮
I'm leaving, Annie.
我要回芝加哥去了
I'm going back to Chicago.
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起，安妮
I'm sorry, Annie.
从你小时候开始
人们就不断让你失望
Ever since you were small,
people been letting you down.
你现在得为自己想想
You gotta
think of yourself now.
你应该去试试那个角色
You should try out
for that part.
噢，我知道你在想什么
Oh, I know
what you're thinking.
每当你去争取一样心爱的东西…
Every time you reach out
for something
you care about...
…命运之手就将它从你面前夺走
fate comes along
and snatches it away.
不过这一次不会的，安妮
But not this time, Annie.
这一次不会的
Not this time.
- 哦，你好，威斯顿先生
- 噢，上帝！
Oh, hello, Mr. Weston.
Oh, jeez.
听着，小姐，我已经跟你说过了
给我办公室打电话
Look, miss,
I told you already,
call my office.
把你的简历给我的秘书
Leave your resume
with my secretary.
我们可以面谈的情况下
我还有必要那么做吗？
Now, why would I want to
do that when we can
talk about it in person?
因为一个聪明的女孩子会那么做的
Because that's what
a smart girl would do.
可我已经把简历给你了
你没有打开就退回来了
But I already
sent you my resume.
You returned it unopened.
我能怎么办？杰克・德里斯库
对跟他合作的演员是非常挑剔的
What can I say? Jack
Driscoll's very particular
about who he works with.
求你，就一次试镜而已
这是我所有的请求
Please, just an audition.
That's all I'm asking.
上帝啊，你不会放弃的，是吧？
Jesus, you don't give up,
do you?
威斯顿先生，我对那个角色烂熟于胸
Mr. Weston,
I know this role backwards.
呃，太糟了
我们刚把那个角色给了别人
Well, that's too bad,
'cause we just gave the part
to someone else.
抱歉，孩子，这出戏已经满员了
I'm sorry, kid.
The play is cast.
我知道现在生计艰难
I know times are tough.
想听我的建议吗？
You want my advice?
用用你的本钱，你长得不难看
Use what you got.
You're not bad-looking.
你这样的女孩子不至于挨饿
A girl like you
doesn't have to starve.
有个新地方，刚刚开业
There's a new place.
It just opened.
现在听着，公主殿下
这地方可不是什么宫殿，明白吗？
Now listen, princess,
this gig ain't the Palace,
you understand?
找肯尼・凯，就说是我叫你去的
Ask for Kenny K.
Tell him I sent you.
把戏做好，把钱拿到手…
Just play the date,
take the money...
然后忘记你曾经去过那里
forget you was ever there.
还有多长？
How much more is there?
还有五盘胶片
Another five reels.
开灯！
Lights up.
就是这个？
This is it?
丹汉姆，就是这花了我们四万美元？
This is what we get
for our $40,000, Denam?
你的另一部冒险电影？
Another one of your
safari pictures?
你向我们许诺说会有布鲁斯・巴克斯特
和玛琳・麦肯济的浪漫场面
You promised us romantic
scenes with Bruce Baxter
and Maureen McKenzie!
少来了，伙计们
你们清楚我们的协议
Come on, fellows,
you know the deal.
我们都同意用玛琳的第一次约会
做卖点…
We agreed to push
Maureers start date...
那样她就可以给她的牙整形了
so she could
get her teeth fixed.
这不是原则的问题，是钱的问题
It's not the principle
of the thing, it's the money.
卡尔，你已经开拍两个月了
Carl,
you've been in production
for over two months.
相信我，只要一上船…
Trust me, Bruce and Maureen
are gonna steam up
the screen...
…布鲁斯和玛琳
就会开始在银幕上大放光彩了
once we get them on the ship.
什么船？
What ship?
就是我们租的
要载我们去目的地的那条船
The one that we hired
to get to the location.
什么目的地，卡尔！
你本应该在布景上拍的
What location? Carl!
You're supposed to be
shooting on the back lot.
是的，我明白
Yes, I understand that.
伙计们
不过我们现在不拍那部电影了…
But, fellows, we're not
making that film anymore...
…我来告诉你们为什么
and I'll tell you why.
故事改变了，剧本改写了
The story has changed.
The script has been rewritten.
真实的生活介入了
Life intervened.
我得到了一份地图
I've come into possession
of a map.
一座连海图上都没有的小岛
唯一一份现存的证据
The sole surviving record
of an uncharted island.
一个被认为只在神话里存在的地方
A place that was
thought to exist
only in myth.
直到今天
Until now.
喂，卡尔，慢点
Whoa, Carl, slow down.
他是要更多的钱吗？
Is he asking for more money?
他是让我们掏钱赞助竹篮打水
He's asking us
to fund a wild-goose chase.
我所说的是一个原始世界
从没有人见过
I'm talking about
a primitive world
never before seen by man.
一个完整文明的遗迹
The ruins
of an entire civilization.
你们所见过的最壮观的景象
The most spectacular thing
you've ever seen.
那里才是我的片场
That's where
I'll shoot my picture.
那会有奶子吗？
Will there be boobies?
奶子？
Boobies?
颤动的乳房，煽情的镜头
Jigglies. Jiblonkas.
Bazooms.
根据我的经验，大家都是奔着…
In my experience,
people only go
to these films...
…土著姑娘的裸体去看这种电影的
to observe the undraped form
of the native girls.
你是白痴吗？
What are you, an idiot?
你觉得他们会问德米尔
他会不会浪费时间在裸体镜头上？
You think they asked De Mille
if he would waste his time
on nudie shots?
不会的，他们尊重电影工作者！
他们是有品味的
No! They respected
the filmmaker.
They showed some class.
你当然不会明白，贱种！
Not that you'd know
what that means,
you cheap lowlife!
你能不能出去一会儿，卡尔？
Would you step out
for a moment, Carl?
索尔曼联合公司
Zelman and Associates.
把那个给我，快点
Give me that, quick.
你不会喜欢的，这里面没有酒精
You won't like it.
It's non-alcoholic.
普雷斯顿
关于电影工业你还有很多东西要学！
Preston, you have
a lot to learn about
the motion picture business.
不要把他打入冷宫，伙计们
毫无疑问他是头脑发热…
Don't write him off, fellows.
He's hotheaded, sure...
…不过卡尔・丹汉姆
还是拍过一些很有趣的作品
but Carl Denam's made
some interesting pictures.
他有很多作品都…接近成功
He's had a lot of
near-success.
他是个自我标榜的自大狂
He's a preening self-promoter.
他有野心，但是没有才华
全身都透着失败
An ambitious no-talent.
The guy's got "loser"
written all over him.
我可以理解你的失望…
I understand
your disappointment...
他根本不会导演，他根本没那个脑子
He can't direct.
He doesn't have the smarts.
他算是完蛋了，地球人都知道
He's washed up.
It's all over town.
这个跳梁小丑会让我们破产的
This jumped-up little turd's
gonna bankrupt us.
这些关于动物的样片能卖出价钱吗？
The animal footage has value.
当然，环球公司非常想要资料片镜头
Sure. Universal are
desperate for stock footage.
那就卖了它，取消拍摄
Then sell it!
Scrap the picture.
我们得从这次惨败中收回点什么
We got to retrieve something
from this debacle.
让他进来
Get him back in.
丹汉姆先生
Mr. Denam.
我需要剧组人员和船员一小时内上船
I want the cast and crew
on the ship within the hour.
不，卡尔，你不能这么干
No, Carl,
you can't do this.
告诉他们制片方催我们提早出发
Tell them the studio
pressured us into
an early departure.
- 这是不合法的
- 你想怎么着？告我，嗯？
It's not ethical!
What are they gonna do,
sue me?
让他们排队去吧
They can get in line.
我不会让他们就这样砍掉我的电影
I'm not gonna let them
kill my film.
你知不知道船上
现在一件摄像设备都没有？
You realize that none of
the camera equipment
is on board?
我们没有许可，没有签证
We have no permits,
no visas.
这就是我雇你的理由，普雷斯顿
That's why I have you,
Preston.
我们没有保险，没有外国货币
We have no insurance,
we have no foreign currency.
实际上我们什么货币也没有
In fact, we have
no currency of any kind.
他在那儿
He's there.
- 进去！
- 谁来付船的费用？
Get in there.
Who's gonna pay
for the ship?
进去！
Get in.
- 你给我出来！出来！
- 踩油门！踩油门！
You get out of there!
Come here!
Step on it! Step on it!
滚出来！你完了，丹汉姆！
Get out!
You're finished, Denam!
别担心，这样的场面我见的多了
Don't worry, Preston.
I've had a lot of practice
at this.
以恶制恶，这个我最拿手
I'm real good
at crapping the crappers.
80度的红牌威士忌…
Red Label, 80% proof...
装在标记“柠檬水”的箱子里
to be packed in a crate
marked "lemonade."
好的
You got it.
告诉玛琳
她可没有六个小时的时间化妆
Tell Maureen
she doesn't have six hours
to put on her face.
如果她想演这部电影的话
她就得上船
If she wants to be
in this picture,
she's gotta be on that boat.
她不想演这部电影
She doesn't wanna be
in this picture.
- 玛琳不干了
- 她不干了？
Maureen pulled out.
She pulled out?
昨天的事，我告诉你了
Yesterday. I told you.
你是跟她说我们要在新加坡拍，对吧？
You said we were shooting
in Singapore, right?
你是这么跟她说的吧？
That's what you told her.
我知道，可我们不在新加坡拍啊
Yeah, but we're not
shooting in Singapore.
该死的，普雷斯顿
你只需要看着她的眼睛扯个谎就行了
God damn it, Preston,
all you had to do was
look her in the eye and lie.
我得找个电话，和哈劳的经纪人谈谈
I got to get to a phone,
talk to harlow's people.
哈劳没有空档
She's unavailable.
梅那・罗伊？克莱儿・波？梅・韦斯？
Myrna Loy? Clara Bow?
Mae West?
她哪能穿得下4号衣服？
You'll never get her
into a size four.
你得找个能穿玛琳的戏服的女孩子
You gotta get a girl
that'll fit into
Maureers costumes.
菲是穿4号
Fay's a size four.
没错，可她现在
正拍着一部雷电华公司的片子
Yes, she is, but she's
doing a picture with RKO.
库珀是吗？
Cooper, huh?
我应该想到的
I might have known.
你根本没听我说，我们得推迟计划
You're not listening.
We got to delay the shoot.
暂停拍摄，今晚我们走不了
Shut production down.
We can't sail tonight.
- 没门！
- 卡尔
Not an option.
Carl.
我说了我能找到那个女孩子
I said I'd find a girl.
看在上帝的分上，普雷斯顿
你需要有成功者的思维方式
For God's sake, Preston,
think like a winner!
给杰克打电话
我需要那个该死的剧本
Call Jack. I need that
goddamn screenplay!
失败永远只是暂时性的
Defeat is always momentary.
（仅限成人）
怎么了？
What?
（艳舞秀 所有座位25美分）
嘿！你要为这个付钱的
Hey! You gonna pay for this?
打扰一下
Excuse me.
女士，我想你掉了这个
Ma'am,
I think you dropped this.
歌舞杂耍，是吗？
Vaudeville, huh?
我参与过一回，观众非常挑剔
I worked vaudeville once.
That is a tough audience.
你不尽快搞定他们，他们就会搞定你
If you don't kill them fast,
they kill you.
丹汉姆先生…
Mr. Denam...
我想告诉你…
I want you to know...
…我不是习惯于接受陌生人施舍的人
that I'm not in the habit
of accepting charity
from strangers.
或者换句话说…
Or, for that matter...
拿不属于我的东西
taking things
that don't belong to me.
刚才显然是可怕的误解
It was obviously
a terrible misunderstanding.
只是我已经很长时间没有拿到过工资了
It's just that
I haven't been paid
in a while.
太糟了，不管怎样，安…
我可以称呼你安吗？
That's awful. Anyway, Ann...
May I call you Ann?
有没有什么可能，你是穿4号的衣服？
You wouldn't happen to be
a size four, by any chance?
不，不，上帝，不
No, no. Oh, God, no.
你完全误会我了，丹劳小姐，拜托
You've got me all wrong.
Miss Darrow, please.
我根本不是你想象的那种人
I'm not that type
of person at all.
那么你是哪种人？
What type of person are you?
我是你可以信任的人，安
我是个电影制片人
I'm someone
you can trust, Ann.
I'm a movie producer.
相信我，我和那些低级趣味
绝对不是一个档次，请坐
Believe me, I am on
the level. No funny business.
Please sit down.
拜托，拜托
Please. Please.
好的
Okay.
安，我要你想象…
Ann, I want you to imagine...
一个前往远东的英俊探险家
a handsome explorer
bound for the Far East.
你们要在远东拍摄？
You're filming
in the Far East?
新加坡
Singapore.
在船上，他遇到了一个神秘的女郎
On board ship,
he meets a mysterious girl.
她迷人，纤弱，心神不宁
She's beautiful,
she's fragile, haunted.
她无法摆脱这样一种感觉――
一种她无法控制的力量…
And she can't
escape the feeling that
forces beyond her control...
…在将她推向一段不归路
are compelling her
down a road from which
she cannot draw back.
就好像她的前半生
都只是这一刻的序幕…
It's as if her whole life
has been a prelude
to this moment...
这改变了一切的，宿命的相遇
this fateful meeting
that changes everything.
理所当然地，有违她理性的判断…
And sure enough, against
her better judgment...
她坠入了爱河
She falls in love.
没错
Yes.
但她对这段感情并没有信心
But she doesn't trust it.
她甚至不能确定
她是不是相信真爱的存在
She's not even sure
if she believes in love.
呃…
Uh...
是吗？
really?
如果她爱上一个人
命中注定是没有结局的
If she loves someone,
it's doomed.
为什么呢？
Why is that?
美好的事物从来都是短暂的
丹汉姆先生
Good things never last,
Mr. Denam.
那么你是感兴趣的
好，这个就算说定了
So you're interested. Good.
That's settled, then.
我不想催你
但是我们在时间方面比较紧迫
Now, I don't wanna rush you,
but we are under
some time pressure.
- 呃，我真的…
- 安！跟你说吧…
Well, I really...
Ann, I'm telling you...
你是最完美的人选，看看你
you're perfect. Look at you.
你是我见过的最悲情的女孩子
You're the saddest girl
I've ever met.
你能让他们哭泣
安，你能让他们心碎
You're gonna make them weep,
Ann. You're gonna
break their hearts.
看，丹汉姆先生
这就是你搞错的地方
See, that's where
you're wrong, Mr. Denam.
我的工作是让人们笑
I make people laugh,
that's what I do.
祝你的电影好运
Good luck with your picture.
安，丹劳小姐，拜托
Ann? Miss Darrow, please!
我会付你给钱的
I'm offering you money.
冒险，名誉，值得一生回味的经历
还有海上的长途旅行
Adventure, fame,
the thrill of a lifetime,
and a long sea voyage.
你想要看剧本的话？
You want to read a script?
我们谈话的同时
杰克・德里斯库正要交稿呢
Jack Driscoll's turning in
a draft as we speak.
杰克・德里斯库？
Jack Driscoll?
当然，怎么了？
Sure. Why?
等等，你认识他？
Wait. You know him?
哦，不认识
我看过他的剧作
No, not personally.
I've seen his plays.
出色的作家，对吗？
我告诉你吧，安…
What a writer, huh?
And let me tell you, Ann...
杰克・德里斯库可不希望
随便什么人来演他的电影
Jack Driscoll does not
want just anyone
starring in this picture.
他对我说，“卡尔…”
He said to me, "Carl...
“有个女孩子是为了这个角色而生的”
"somewhere out there
is a woman
born to play this role."
我一看到你，就明白了
And as soon as I saw you,
I knew.
明白什么？
Knew what?
那个女孩子只可能是你
It was always
going to be you.
- 我还欠你多少？
- 25美分
How much do I owe you?
Make it a quarter.
零钱不用找了
Keep the change.
这就是我们的摄影船？
Is this
the moving picture ship?
不完全是
Not exactly.
实际上是这边的这艘
It's actually
this one over here.
（冒险号）
不要被表面现象蒙蔽了
船上实际宽敞许多
Don't let appearances
deceive you. It's much more
spacious on board.
- 这就是所有设备？
- 对
Is this all of the equipment?
Yeah.
- 全都在这里了？
- 对
This is all of it?
Yeah.
- 我们带上“贝灵巧”影像设备了吗？
- 是的
We're taking
the Bell & howell?
Yeah.
- 很好，你拿了所有的镜头？
- 当然
Good. You got all the lenses?
Sure.
- 卡尔？
- 我在这里
Carl!
Yes!
- 上船吧，伙计们，快
- 来吧
Get it on board, fellows,
come on.
不好了，不好了
It's bad, it's bad.
他们正在路上，我刚刚听说
They're on their way.
I've just had word.
- 谁？
- 穿制服的
Who?
Men in uniform.
电影公司叫了警察
The studio called the cops.
安格霍恩！解缆！
Englehorn! Cast off!
升帆，起锚…
Hoist up the mainsail,
raise the anchor...
随便你怎么办
我们得出发了！
whatever the hell it is
you do. We gotta leave!
这个我办不到
I cannot do that.
我们在等舱单
We are waiting
on the manifest.
等谁？请说英语，谢谢
What? Who? English, please.
必须的文件，丹汉姆先生
Paperwork, Mr. Denam.
现在走的话我再给你一千
I'll give you another $1,000
to leave now.
开始的一千你还没有给呢
You haven't given me
the first $1,000 yet.
我们能不能以后再说？
Can we talk about this later?
你没看见我们有贵宾在这里吗？
Can't you see
we're in the company
of a VIP guest?
女士
Ma'am.
我是安・丹劳
Ann Darrow.
那么你准备好这次旅行了，丹劳小姐？
So you are ready
for this voyage, Miss Darrow?
当然
Sure.
紧张吗？
Nervous?
紧张？不紧张
Nervous? No.
为什么这么问？我应该紧张吗？
Why? Should I be?
不是每个女人都愿意冒这样的险
It isn't every woman
who would take such a risk.
为什么不让我来领丹劳小姐
去她的舱位呢？
Why don't I show
Miss Darrow to her cabin?
好主意，谢谢，普雷斯顿
Wonderful idea.
Thank you, Preston.
丹劳小姐，如果您不介意…
Miss Darrow,
if you would just...
嗨，我叫普雷斯顿，卡尔的助手
hi. My name is Preston.
Carl's assistant.
说好了两千，你收支票吗？
$2,000. It's a deal.
Will you take a check?
我有其它选择吗？
Do I have a choice?
请跟我来
Please follow me.
如果你有任何需要…
借过一下，伙计们
If there's anything
that you...
Excuse me, fellows.
如果你有任何需要，请尽管开口
If there's anything
that you need,
please don't hesitate to ask.
噢，上帝！杰克，你吓死我了
Oh, Jesus!
Jack, you scared me.
听着，如果有任何人来敲门，别开
你也从来没有见过我
Listen. If anyone comes
to the door, don't open it.
You haven't seen me.
就说我得了抑郁症自杀了
Say I got depressed
and committed suicide.
说我把头浸在了马桶里
Say I stuck my head
down the toilet.
- 想来点吗？
- 不行，卡尔，我得走了
You want one?
No. I can't stay, Carl.
我有个排练
已经迟到三个小时了
I got a rehearsal for which
I am now three hours late.
- 这是什么？
- 剧本
What's this?
It's the script.
这就是剧本？
This is a script?
杰克，只有15页
Jack, this is 15 pages.
我知道，可它们都很精彩
你拿到了精彩的15页，卡尔
I know, but they're good.
You've got 15 good pages
there, Carl.
我可是要拍一部全长的电影
I'm supposed to be making
a feature-length picture.
你原来跟我说还有更多时间的
抱歉，我得走了
You told me I had more time.
I'm sorry. Look, I gotta go.
不行，杰克，你不能这么对我
我有了开端…
No, Jack, you can't
do this to me.
I have a beginning...
…可我需要经过和结局
我得有东西可拍
but I need a middle
and an end. I gotta have
something to shoot.
听着，你有我的注释
我得走了，朋友，回头见
Look, you got my notes.
I got to go, pal. See you.
好，好吧，你也许想了结一下
All right, fine.
We might as well settle up.
你要付我钱？
You're gonna pay me?
不会让朋友吃亏的
I'm not gonna stiff a friend.
我从来不知道，你还会主动给人钱
I've never known you
to volunteer cash before.
两千怎么样？
How's $2,000 sound?
太好了
Sounds great.
我觉得也是
I thought it might.
- 太好了
- 好吧
Sounds great.
Okay.
拉起缆绳！
Raise the spring line!
注意船尾！
Watch the aft!
好了
And voila.
谢了
Thanks.
卡尔，你…你写的是“两千”
You've written "two grand."
可不是嘛，抱歉
我们从头再写一次
So I did. Sorry about that.
Let's start from
the beginning.
“贰仟美元”
"Two thousand dollars."
今天是29号，对吗？
It is the 29th, isn't it?
少来，是25号，是25号
Oh, come on, it's the 25th.
It's the 25th.
上帝，真抱歉，只需要多花点时间
God, I'm sorry.
It'll just take a sec.
行了，卡尔，等你回来再付我钱吧
Never mind, Carl.
Just pay me
when you get back.
好吧
All right.
巴克斯特先生
您的舱位在左手边最后一间
Your cabin is the last
on the left, Mr. Baxter.
请允许我表达
对您回到我们中间的兴奋之情
And may I just say how
excited we are to have you
back with us, sir?
省省吧，帮把手好吗？
Be a sport
and lend a hand here,
would you?
抱歉，我得…我必需要下…
Excuse me. I'm trying to...
I gotta get...
上帝！
Christ!
非常感谢你的帮助，伙计
Appreciate the help, fellow.
我来给您开门
Let me get the door for you.
欢迎来到您的客房，先生
Welcome to your
stateroom, sir.
双机极低速前进，赫斯先生
Dead slow ahead both,
Mr. Hayes.
船长，双机微速前进
Dead slow ahead both,
Captain.
哦，该死
Oh, Christ!
妈的！
God damn it!
我一直在告诫你，杰克
在剧院是赚不到钱的
I keep telling you, Jack,
there's no money in theater.
噢，不，不
Oh, no! No!
你最好还是来干电影
You're much better off
sticking with film.
卡尔，我干这个不是为了钱
I don't do it
for the money, Carl.
我碰巧爱上了剧院
I happen to love the theater.
不，你并不爱
No, you don't.
如果你真爱的话…
If you really loved it...
…刚才就跳下去了
you would have jumped.
是你！这都是你的错！
You! This is your fault!
这里非常舒适的
有充足的昏黄光线，新鲜的干草
This room very comfortable.
Plenty dim light,
fresh straw.
天，这下面装的是什么？
Jesus. What do you keep
down here?
狮子，老虎，河马，应有尽有
Lion, tiger, hippo,
you name it.
卖给动物园吗？
You sell them to zoos?
动物园，马戏团
Zoo, circus.
船长卖珍稀动物赚了不少钱哪
Skipper get big money
for rare animal.
小心，地板上有骆驼尿
Careful. Camel have
bad accident on floor.
擦不掉的污迹
Stain unremovable.
船长可以抓到你想要的任何动物
Skipper catch
any wild animal you want.
你想要白犀牛的话他可以给你个好价钱
He'll do you real good price
on white rhino.
老崔！
Choy.
没能给您提供舱位我非常抱歉
My apologies for not being
able to offer you a cabin.
找到符合您品味的笼子了吗？
Have you found an enclosure
to your taste?
怎么选都烂
Spoiled for choice.
您是什么呢，德里斯库先生？
狮子？
What are you, Mr. Driscoll?
A lion?
还是黑猩猩？
Or a chimpanzee?
我就要这一间吧
I'll take this one.
（氯仿）
（注 麻醉剂）
我告诉过你要锁起来
I told you to lock it up.
- 对不起，船长，兰皮说…
- 这里不是兰皮发号施令！
Sorry, Skipper. Lumpy said...
Lumpy doesn't
give the orders!
你要干什么？想要整船人都睡着吗？
What are you trying to do?
Put the whole ship to sleep?
把它们搬走
Get them out of here.
（主演 布鲁斯・巴克斯特）
（亚马逊部落新娘）
- 厨师的特别奉献
- 好的
Compliments of the chef.
Okay.
噢，上帝，俺的神啊
Oh, Christ. Oh, God.
羊脑配核桃味汁
Lamb's brains
in walnut sauce.
吉米
Jimmy.
你照我说的把绳子绕在甲板上了吗？
You run those ropes
up on deck like I told you?
现在就去，赫斯先生
Doing it now, Mr. Hayes.
先把德里斯库先生的钢笔
还给他怎么样？
How about you return
Mr. Driscoll's pen first?
他没有恶意的
He don't mean no harm.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 我不会让他再来了
- 没关系的
I'll keep him
out of your way.
It's okay.
他很喜欢这个地方
It's just that
he likes it down here.
这里也是四年以前我发现他的地方
It's where I found him
four years ago.
装在后面的一个笼子里
Stowed away
in one of them back cages.
胳膊两处骨折
His arm was broken
in two places.
他比这里一半以上的动物还要野
He was wilder than
half the animals in here.
现在都不肯告诉我他从哪里来
Still won't tell me
where he came from.
不管是哪，那绝对不是什么好地方
But it wasrt anyplace good.
你得搞搞清楚
You got to straighten up.
吉米
Jimmy.
你不会想
后半辈子都待在这条船上的
You don't want to
be on this ship
the rest of your life.
- 我想的
- 不，你不想的，吉米
Yes, I do.
No, you don't, Jimmy.
你要聪明一点，受点教育
You got to be smart.
Get yourself educated.
给自己多点选择，你要认真对待！
Give yourself some options.
Take this seriously!
我有啊，赫斯先生，你看
I do, Mr. Hayes, I do. Look.
我已经在读书了
I've been reading.
你从哪里搞到的？
Where'd you get this?
跟别人借的
I borrowed it.
（纽约市公立图书馆）
长…长期借阅
On long-term loan.
看，看，看这个
Look at this. Look, look.
《不定期货船上的冒险》
瞧见了吗？就跟我们一样
"Adventures on
a tramp steamer."
See? Just like us.
见到你太高兴了，德里斯库先生
It's so nice to meet you,
Mr. Driscoll.
实际上我很熟悉你的作品，没错
I'm actually quite familiar
with your work, yes.
你好，德里斯库先生
很高兴见到你
Hello, Mr. Driscoll.
It's so nice to meet you.
实际上我相当熟悉你的作品
Actually, I'm quite familiar
with your work.
我是你的忠实崇拜者
I'm a huge fan.
我读过你写的所有东西
I've read everything
you've ever written.
太过了
No, too much.
整段对白里都有船的引擎噪声
Gonna have the ship's engines
all over the dialogue.
海鸥
Seagulls.
摄影机的噪音，风声
上帝才知道还有什么
Camera noise. Wind.
Christ knows what else.
我不管，麦克
I don't care, Mike.
你是音响师，你来搞定
You're the sound recordist.
Make it work.
安！快进来
我来给你介绍剧组里的其他人
Ann! Come on in.
Let me introduce you
to the crew.
这是赫伯，摄影师
This is herb, the cameraman.
- 很荣幸认识你，女士
- 我也一样
Delighted to meet you, ma'am.
Likewise.
这裙子真是太美丽了
May I say
what a lovely dress?
这件旧衣服？我只是随便穿穿
Oh, this old thing?
I just threw it on.
这不是玛琳的戏服吗？
Isn't that
one of Maureers costumes?
呃，女孩子要做点什么
才能吃到早饭呢？
Now, what does a girl
have to do around here
to get some breakfast?
兰皮，你听到女士说的话了？
Lumpy, you heard the lady.
想尝尝我的麦片粥吗？
里面还有核桃仁
Fancy my porridge
a la walnuts?
噢，安，我相信你还不认识…
Oh, Ann, I don't believe
you've met...
安？
Ann?
没关系，丹汉姆先生
我知道这位是谁
That's all right, Mr. Denam.
I know who this is.
见到你诚惶诚恐
非常荣幸能参与演出
Thrilled to meet you.
It's an honor to be
a part of this.
天，谢谢你
Gee, thanks.
实际上我非常熟悉你的作品
Actually, I'm quite familiar
with your work.
真的吗？
Really?
对，我最崇拜的是…
Yes,
and what I most admire...
…你捕捉普通人声音的方式
is the way
you've captured the voice
of the common people.
这个嘛，我的工作就是如此
Well, that's my job.
我相信以前也有人这么说过
德里斯库先生…
I'm sure you've heard
this before, Mr. Driscoll...
如果你不介意的话，我想说…
if you don't mind me
saying...
你和照片上一点也不象
but you don't look at all
like your photograph.
- 抱歉
- 等等，安…
Excuse me.
Wait a minute, Ann...
本人看起来年轻的多，也帅得多
he's so much
younger in person.
And much better-looking.
安，别说了，别说了
Ann, stop. Stop right there.
你知道，我只是担心你或许是…
You see, I was just afraid
that you might be...
…是那种自恋的“作家”
one of those
self-obsessed literary types.
- 抱歉，我不是…
- 你知道…
I'm sorry, I'm not...
You know...
那种只会把头埋在书本里…
the tweedy twerp
with his nose in his book
and his head up his a...
见到你也很高兴，丹劳小姐
It's nice to meet you, too,
Miss Darrow.
哦，上帝啊
Good Christ!
她站在栏杆边
She's standing
at the railing.
她还不知道…
She doesn't know it yet...
但是他们正向灾难驶去
写下来了吗？
But they are sailing
towards disaster.
You got that?
好，那么她转过身来…
Okay, so she turns...
大副向她摇晃着走来
the first mate
is staggering towards her.
刀从他的背后直透前胸
There's a knife
sticking out of his back.
等等，我们要把大副干掉？
Wait a sec. We're killing off
the first mate?
我们首先得假设她知道大副是谁
That's assuming she knows
who the first mate is.
少来了，杰克
这只是个正直的过失
Come on, Jack.
It was an honest mistake.
安是个近视眼，谁都有可能
Ann is nearsighted.
It could have happened
to anyone.
我是在开玩笑，卡尔
I was joking, Carl.
关键在于她非常害怕，她向别处看去
The point is,
she's horrified.
She has to look away.
就在这时她看到了它
And that's when she sees it.
看到了什么？
Sees what?
什么呀？
What?
那个岛
The island.
我们现在要到某个岛上去拍摄？
什么时候决定的事？
We're filming on an island
now? When did this happen?
嘘，杰克，小点声
Jack, keep your voice down.
我不想要船员毛骨悚然
I don't want the crew
getting spooked.
为什么他们会毛骨悚然？
岛叫什么名字？
Why would they get spooked?
What's it called?
好吧
那个岛有个当地的名字…
All right.
It has a local name...
不过我警告你，杰克，它可不怎么好听
but I'm warning you, Jack,
it doesn't sound good.
他们叫它骷髅岛
They call it Skull Island.
你明白了吗？
Did you get that?
这地方有什么问题？
What's wrong
with this place?
这个地方没有什么经官方证实的问题
There's nothing
officially wrong with it.
因为从技术角度讲，它还没有被发现呢
Because, technically,
it hasn't been
discovered yet.
好，好吧
Okay. All right.
那么我们就到了这个地方
So we arrive at this place.
S...
K...
U...
L...
骷髅岛
Island.
好的，上面的人注意，开始！
All right, everyone,
from the top! And action!
实在太让人兴奋了
我以前从来没坐过船
I think this is
awfully exciting! I've never
been on a ship before.
我以前从没坐过有女人的船
And I've never been on one
with a woman before.
我想你们在船上不太会想女人，对吗？
I guess you don't think
much of women
on ships, do you?
是啊，她们太麻烦了
No, they're a nuisance.
- 我会尽量不给你们添麻烦的
- 你在我们周围就已经是麻烦了
Well, I'll try not to be.
Just being around is trouble.
停！
Cut!
非常好
It's great.
布鲁斯，演得非常好
你可以放松10分钟
Bruce, wonderful performance.
You can relax for 10 minutes.
表演非常自然，我都被感动了
That was very natural.
I felt moved.
你觉得怎么样，德里斯库
对白现在不那么生硬了，对吧？
What do you think, Driscoll?
Dialogue's got some
flow now, huh?
真是完全的感情流露啊
It was pure effluence.
我加了点善意的嘲弄而已
I beefed up the banter.
还是克制这种冲动吧
Try to resist that impulse.
只是一点幽默感罢了，朋友
It's just a little bit
of humor, bud.
你是什么？布尔什维克吗？
What are you,
a Bolshevik or something?
演员哪
Actors.
踏遍整个世界，却只能看到一面镜子
Travel the world,
but all they ever see
is a mirror.
好漂亮的腿（也是晕船的意思）
Good legs.
是晕船的意思，呃，你知道，晕船
Sea legs.
Well, you know, sea legs.
耶
Yeah.
不是说你没有漂亮的腿
只是不小心说出来了
Not that you don't
have good legs.
Just making conversation.
上帝啊，丹劳小姐！
Jesus. Miss Darrow!
今天你和布鲁斯的那场戏…
About the scene today
with you and Bruce...
我知道你不是那么写的…
I know it wasrt
what you wrote...
可巴克斯特先生强烈地认为
如果一个男人喜欢一个女人…
but Mr. Baxter
felt very strongly that
when a man likes a woman...
那么他一定要忽视她的存在
he must ignore her.
如果敌意真的变得很深…
And if things turn
really hostile, then...
不会吗？
No?
这是个有趣的理论
Interesting theory.
我知道，我应该…
I know. I should have...
这并非我本意，不过…
It wasrt
what I had intended, but...
抱歉，我…
I'm sorry. I was...
你做了自己的诠释
And you made it your own.
我当时好紧张
I was nervous.
- 当时很滑稽，实际上
- 你当时是很滑稽
It was funny, actually.
You were funny.
拜托别再说下去了，晚安
Please don't say
another word. Good night.
丹劳小姐
Miss Darrow.
你不用紧张
You don't have to be nervous.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们再…
Let's take it...
你可不可以…
我们这儿正在拍，谢谢
Would you please...
We're trying to
shoot a scene.
- 好的
- 多谢
Okay.
Thank you.
好的，再来
Okay, again.
我们快到了，转向西南
We're close. Turn southwest.
西南方向上千英里内都没有陆地
There's no land southwest
for thousands of miles.
我们离正常航线越来越远
It takes us way outside
the shipping lanes.
我不能摸黑在这片水域行驶
I won't sail blind
in these waters.
我会补偿你的
I'll make it
won'th your while.
那里什么也没有
There's nothing out there.
那样的话，你也不会失去什么
Well,
then you've nothing to lose.
如果有人对你说
这条船没有驶向新加坡…
If someone were to tell you
this ship was headed
for Singapore...
…你会怎么说？
what would you say?
我会说千真万确，赫斯先生
I would say they're
full of it, Mr. Hayes.
昨天晚上我们转向西南了
Well, we turned southwest
last night.
先生们，拜托
Gentlemen, please.
- 我们不想找麻烦
- 不
We're not looking
for trouble.
No.
你们在找别的什么东西
You're looking
for something else.
对，你说得对
Yes, we are.
我们要找到骷髅岛
We're going to find
Skull Island.
找到它，拍摄下来，展示给整个世界
Find it, film it,
and show it to the world.
只要花25美分
你就可以看到地图上最后的空白
For 25 cents,
you get to see the last
blank space on the map.
我不知道那是不是好事
I wouldn't be
so sure of that.
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
七年前我和赫斯先生
一起工作在…
Seven years ago,
me and Mr. Hayes
were working our passage...
…一艘挪威帆船上
on a Norwegian bark.
我们从水中救起了一个海难的幸存者
We picked up a castaway.
We found him in the water.
他已经漂了很多天了
He'd been drifting for days.
他们的船在一个岛上搁浅了
在苏门答腊以西很远的地方
His ship had run aground
on an island
way west of Sumatra.
一座隐藏在迷雾中的岛
An island hidden in fog.
他说起一道巨大的城墙…
He spoke of a huge wall...
建于久远的年代…
built so long ago...
没有人知道是谁建造了它
no one knew who'd made it.
墙高100英尺…
A wall 100 foot high...
现在仍然和建成时一样坚固
as strong today
as it was ages ago.
他们为什么要建一道墙呢？
Why'd they build the wall?
那个幸存者，他说起一个生物…
Well, the castaway,
he spoke of a creature...
既非野兽，也非人类…
neither beast nor man...
但的确有可怕的生物
就活在那座墙后
but something monstrous,
living behind that wall.
一头老虎或者狮子？
A lion or a tiger.
或者是吃人的家伙？
所有故事都是这么开始的
A man-eater. That's how
all these stories start.
他还说什么了？
What else did he say?
什么也没说
Nothing.
第二天早晨我们发现
他的心脏上插了一把刀
We found him
the next morning. He'd stuck
a knife through his heart.
Mmm-hmm.
抱歉，伙计们，编故事编好点
Sorry, fellows.
You'll have to do
better than that.
怪兽，只在B级电影里才出现
Monsters belong in B movies.
如果你找到这个地方…
If you find this place...
如果你和你的朋友们
还有你们的摄像机一起上岸的话…
if you go ashore
with your friends
and your cameras...
你们就永远也回不来了
you won't come back.
只是想要你们明白这一点
Just as long as
you understand that.
（迷雾）
你认为我们会在这里待多长时间？
How long do you expect us
to stay out here?
你在写一出舞台喜剧？
You're writing a stage comedy?
我为你而写的
I'm writing it for you.
你为什么要这么做？
Why would you do that?
- 为什么我要为你写一出戏？
- 是啊
Why would I write
a play for you?
Yes.
这还不明显吗？
Isn't it obvious?
对我来说不是
Not to me.
这个嘛…
Well...
在潜台词里已经说明了
it's in the subtext.
那我一定是没看到
I guess
I must have missed it.
不是言语上的
It's not about words.
给你的，船长
Message for you, Captain.
出什么事情了？
What's going on?
赫斯
我们为什么要改变航向？
Hayes,
why are we changing course?
- 安格霍恩，你不能…
- 外面说！
Englehorn, you can't just...
Outside.
你的逮捕证已经下发了
There's a warrant out
for your arrest.
这个你知道吗？
Did you know that?
我已经下命令转驶向仰光了
I've been ordered
to divert to Rangoon.
再给我一个星期
我的电影还没有拍成
Another week.
I haven't got a film yet.
求求你，我把我的一切都押上了
Please. I have risked
everything I have on this.
不，丹汉姆，你把我的一切都押上了
No, Denam.
You risked everything I have.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
告诉我你想要什么？
我什么都可以给你
Tell me what you want.
I'll give you anything.
我想要你下船
I want you off my ship.
设定到仰光的航向，赫斯先生
Set a course for Rangoon,
Mr. Hayes.
我完蛋了
I'm finished.
对我来说结束了，杰克
It's over for me, Jack.
你认为会有怎样的结局呢，卡尔？
How'd you think
this would end, Carl?
检查一下我们的位置，用星星
Check our position.
Use the stars.
天上没有星星，船长
There are no stars, Captain.
这是什么？
What is that?
- 什么东西？
- 这个
What?
That.
这个，就在这儿
That right there.
不知道，是什么？也许是咖啡渍吧
I don't know.
What is it? A coffee stain?
守好前方观望台
告诉我测深索的深度
Station the forward lookout
and get me the depth
by lead line.
是，船长
Aye, Captain.
30英寻，没见底！
（注 英寻为长度单位）
30 fathoms, no bottom!
减速，只用低速
Reduce speed,
steerage way only.
双机低速前进
Dead slow ahead, both.
你应该停船
You should stop the ship.
左舵15度
15 degrees port.
赫斯先生，我们会走出去的
We're getting out of here,
Mr. Hayes.
我们会找到没有雾的区域的
We'll find clear conditions.
测到海底了！
We have seabed!
25英寻！
25 fathoms!
水越来越浅了！
We're shallowing!
右舵20度！
20 degrees starboard!
船长，你根本不知道你正驶向哪里！
Captain, you don't know
where the hell you're going!
再去读个深度！
Get me another reading!
再读一次深度！
Another reading!
22英寻！
22 fathoms!
- 把灯关掉
- 是，船长
Douse the lights.
Aye, Captain.
10英寻！
10 fathoms!
城墙！正前方有堵墙！
Wall! There's a wall ahead!
关闭发动机！
Stop engines!
给我点动力！半速前进！
Give me some power!
Half astern both.
半速前进，船长！
Half astern both, Captain!
礁石！
Rocks!
右舷有礁石，船长！
Rocks to starboard, Captain!
左舷也有礁石！到处都是礁石！
To port! Rocks everywhere!
你来掌舵，赫斯
Take the wheel, hayes.
抓住！
Hang on!
全速前进！
Full ahead!
左舷有礁石，船长！
Rocks to port, Captain!
- 躲过了，船长
- 右舷！右舷！
Turn, Captain!
Starboard, starboard!
啊！
Ah!
把这个洞堵上！
Shore up that breach!
给我找更多人下来！
来吧，快点，快！
Get me more men
down here now!
Come on, move, move!
- 赫斯！
- 船被狠狠撞了一下！
Hayes!
She's taken a pounding!
推进器怎么样？
What about the prop?
如我们现在所知，主轴没弯
The shaft's not bent,
as far as we can tell.
我们卡在礁石上了！
But she struck hard
against the rock!
船长！
Captain!
你最好快点上来！
Better come up quick!
就在那儿！
Right there!
你想让我带他们回来吗？
Want me to bring them back?
卡尔・丹汉姆关我屁事
I don't give a damn
about Carl Denam.
下次涨潮之前要把这条船修好！
I want this ship fixed
and ready to float
on the next high tide!
快点，加油干！
Come on, move it.
我们要走了，赫斯先生
We're leaving, Mr. Hayes.
你能相信吗，杰克？
Can you believe this, Jack?
我们的电影拍成了
We've got our picture.
为什么马洛非要逆流而上呢？
Why does Marlow
keep going up the river?
他为什么不回头？
Why doesn't he turn back?
有一个“他”想要那么做，吉米
There's a part of him
that wants to, Jimmy.
他心底有个声音在发出警告
A part deep inside himself
that sounds a warning.
可是那另一个“他”…
But there's another part...
需要去探索个究竟
that needs to know.
好打败那让他恐惧的东西
To defeat the thing
which makes him afraid.
“我们过去无法理解
因为我们身在遥远的彼方…”
"We could not understand
because we were too far...
“我们也早已淡忘…”
"and could not renenber...
“因为那旅行
是穿过史前时代的长夜…”
"because we were traveling
in the night of first ages...
“而那时代早已远去…
"of those ages
that are gone...
“了无踪迹，也没有回忆”
"leaving hardly a sign,
and no nenories.
“我们已经司空见惯了…”
"We are accustoned to look...
“带着沉重枷锁的被征服的巨兽…”
"upon the shackled forn
of a conquered nonster...
“但在那里…”
"but there...
“在那里你会见到
一个凶残并且无拘无束的它”
"there you could look
at a thing
nonstrous and free."
这不是个冒险故事…
It's not
an adventure story...
对吗，赫斯先生？
is it, Mr. Hayes?
对，吉米
No, Jimmy.
不是
It's not.
- 这是个荒废了的地方
- 这当然是个被荒废的地方
It's deserted.
Of course it's deserted.
睁开眼睛看看，普雷斯顿
这地方就是个废墟
Use your eyes, Preston.
The place is a ruin.
成百上千年没有人住过了
Nobody's lived here
for hundreds of years.
丹汉姆先生，我想我们该回去了
Mr. Denam,
I think we should go back.
这个我来处理
I will handle this.
（牛奶巧克力）
看，巧克力
Look. Chocolate.
你喜欢巧克力吗？
You like chocolate?
很好吃的
It's good to eat.
想要吗？
You want?
拿着吧
Take it.
这里，拿在手里吧，拿着
Here, put it in your hand
and take it.
看在上帝的份上，丹汉姆
别跟这些土著纠缠了
For God's sakes, Denam,
leave the native alone.
她不想要你的巧克力
She doesn't want
the chocolate.
啊！
Aah!
没事的！
All right!
只是女人和老人！
Just a bunch of women
and old folks!
不会有危险的！
They're harmless!
安！
Ann!
杰克！
Jack.
这下开眼了吧
Seen enough?
给船减轻重量！
Lighten the ship!
不是必需的东西都扔下去！
Anything that's not
bolted down goes overboard!
举起来！
Just heave it!
我们逃出来了
We got away.
我们得心存感激，先生们
We gotta be grateful
for that, gentlemen.
那麦克呢？他可没逃出来
他现在都还在那儿呢！
What about Mike?
He didn't get away!
He's still there!
麦克死得其所！
他的死不是没有价值的
Mike died doing
what he believed in!
He didn't die for nothing.
我再告诉你一件事
我会为了麦克把这部电影拍完的！
And I'll tell you
something else. I'm gonna
finish this film for Mike!
我会把它拍完的…
I'll finish it...
我还要把影片的收益捐给…
and I'll donate
the proceeds...
他的妻子和孩子
to his wife and kids.
因为那人是个英雄
他应该得到这样的荣誉
Because that man is a hero,
and he deserves nothing less.
听啊，听！
Hear, hear!
除了土豆，把能扔的都扔掉
Chuck everything
except for the potatoes!
- 这到底是怎么了
- 抱歉，莎士比亚
What's wrong now?
Excuse me, Shakespeare.
来吧，老兄，来吧，快点
Come on, men! Come on, hurry!
把那些多余的缆绳扔掉！快啊，扔掉！
Drop those
spare cables overboard!
Go on, just chuck it!
- 安在哪里？
- 什么？
Where's Ann?
What?
安在哪里？
Where's Ann?
安！
Ann!
脱离困境了！
She's free!
双机全速前进！
Full ahead, both engines!
安！
Ann!
不！停船！回去！
No! Stop! Turn back!
停船！
Stop!
我们必须掉头
We have to turn back.
他们抢走了安
They've taken Ann.
No!
刚！刚！刚！
Kong! Kong! Kong!
全体人员准备上岸！报告位置！
All hands going ashore!
Report to stations!
快点，快点，先生们！
Jump to it!
Jump to it, gentlemen!
我们正在快，赫斯先生！
We're doing it, Mr. Hayes!
来吧，快点！
Come on, move it!
用力划！
Pull harder!
划啊！划啊！
Row! Row!
加油！
Come on!
刚
Kong.
散开来，找到她！
Spread out! Find her!
丹劳小姐！
Miss Darrow!
- 去那边找，吉米！
- 所有人不要走散了！
Check up there, Jimmy!
Everybody stay together!
安！
Ann!
她应该就在附近！
She's here somewhere!
上帝啊，那是什么东西？
What in God's name was that?
在城墙后面！
Behind the wall!
城墙后面！
她不见了！
She's gone!
卡尔，怎么了？
Carl, what is it?
你见到什么了？
You saw something.
赫斯带15个人跟你们去
You can take hayes
and 15 others.
我派人守卫城门，直到你们回来
I'll put a guard on the gate
until you return.
其他人在船上等
The rest of you
stay with the ship.
老崔！
Choy!
吉米，你不去
Not you, Jimmy.
不要这样，赫斯先生，看看他们
Come on, Mr. Hayes.
Look at them.
没人会用枪
None of them knows
which way to point a gun.
你呆在这里
Stay here.
- 丹劳小姐需要我！
- 不！
Miss Darrow needs me!
No!
带上三角架跟其他拍摄设备
Bring the tripod
and all of the film stock.
你要六寸长焦镜头吗？
You wanna go
with the 6-inch lens?
普通广角镜足够了
The wide-angle
will do just fine.
你们有枪，有食物，有弹药
You got guns. You got food.
You got the ammo.
给你们24小时！
And you got 24 hours!
24小时啊
24 hours?
明天这个时候我们启锚
This time tomorrow,
we haul anchor.
丹劳小姐！
Miss Darrow!
安！
Ann!
丹劳小姐！
Miss Darrow!
那是什么？
What is it?
开火！
Fire!
阻止它
Cut it out.
停火
Hold your fire.
停止开火！
Hold your fire!
趴下，妈的，趴下
Stay down, damn it.
Stay down.
来啊，来啊
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
打的好，赫斯先生
Good shooting, Mr. Hayes.
这些东西不是绝种了么？
Arert these things supposed
to be extinct?
他们现在是了
They are now.
这他妈到底是什么地方？
What the hell
kind of a place is this?
丹劳小姐！
Miss Darrow!
安！
Ann!
不！
No!
- 安！
- 丹劳小姐！
Ann!
Miss Darrow!
安！
Ann!
好家伙，这里好像流着血的坟场
Christ,
it's a bleeding boneyard!
他们都被分肢了
They've been ripped
limb from limb.
安！安！
Ann! Ann!
赫斯先生，继续走就是了
当没看见我
Just keep walking, Mr. Hayes.
Pretend you didn't see me.
- 耶稣基督啊，吉米
- 我需要那把枪
Jesus, Jimmy.
Hey, I need that!
我不会给你枪的
I'm not giving you a gun!
他们发枪给你的时候比我还小！
You were younger than me
when they gave you one!
我那是在陆军里，有教练士官教我
I was in the Army.
I was trained.
I had a drill sergeant.
我想帮忙找她回来
I wanna help bring her back.
不要让我后悔
Don't make me regret it.
节省弹药
Conserve your ammunition!
我都累死了
I'm knackered.
- 我不能呼吸了
- 我需要人工呼吸
I gotta have a breather.
Great idea.
伙计们，没时间了
Fellows, we don't have
time for this.
我们已经延误了，起来吧！
We've lost too much ground
already. Come on, get up!
他们需要休息，放松一下
They're not about to
quit on you.
Cut them some slack.
你们可以休息5分钟
All right,
you got five minutes!
所有人都在待在我的视线以内
Everybody stay in sight.
到这边来
我要给峡谷拍一个广角
Over here. I'm gonna get
a wide shot of the valley.
血腥诺拉！
Bloody Nora!
就是这东西抓走了丹劳小姐？
Is that
what took Miss Darrow?
只有一种生物可以
留下这么大的脚印
There's only one creature
capable of leaving
a footprint that size.
恐怖的雪人
The abominable snowman.
是啊，雪人，我们是刀板上的鱼肉了
Yeah, a snowman.
We dead meat.
那东西得多大，20，25英尺高？
It's got to be what,
20, 25 feet?
卡尔看到过
Carl saw it.
我们问问他
Let's ask him.
丹汉姆！
Denam!
他跑哪里去了？
Where'd he go?
走过去，布鲁斯
Walk forward, Bruce.
- 什么？
- 你是片子主角
What?
You're the star
of this picture.
进入角色，走向那群动物
Get into character
and head toward the animals.
这里到底是他妈的什么地方啊
What the hell
kind of a place is this?
你确定这能行吗，丹汉姆？
Are you sure about this,
Denam?
这种事没替身的吗？
Don't we have a stand-in
for this type of thing?
我要你在镜头里
不然别人说这是假的
I need you in the shot,
or people will say
they're fake.
没人会说这是假的
Nobody's gonna think
these are fake.
你让它们紧张了，别突然乱动
You're making them nervous.
No sudden movements.
我没动
I'm not moving.
上帝他妈啊
Mother of God.
怎么回事？
What's this?
怎么了，怎么了？卡尔在哪？
What is it? What is it?
Where's Carl?
卡尔？他…他在那边，拍电影
Carl?
He's up there, filming.
小心！
Bugger this!
Watch out.
跑啊，杰克！
Run, Jack!
耶稣基督啊，快走，吉米，跑啊！
Holy Christ.
Go, Jimmy, run!
跑，跑，跑啊！
Run, run, run!
- 你放手
- 我不会丢下摄影机的
Let go!
I'm not leaving the camera!
快放手，你个笨蛋
Let go, you idiot!
卡尔，快跑
Carl, run!
趴下
Look out!
看着点！
过来了！
Coming through!
不！
No!
Come on.
卡尔！卡尔！
Carl! Carl!
起来！快走，快走
Get up! Come on. Come on.
丹汉姆先生！丹汉姆先生！
Mr. Denam! Mr. Denam!
赫伯，赫伯！快点！
Herb! Herb, come on!
抓住三角架！
Take the tripod!
来啊！
Come on!
我把你拉上来，抓紧了支脚
I'm pulling you up!
Hold on to your end!
走吧！
Go!
不，没你我哪儿也不去
No, I'm not going anywhere
without you!
- 你应该离开我
- 闭嘴，抓住了
You gotta leave me!
Shut up and hold on!
吉米，算算人头数
Jimmy, do a head count.
我想知道有多少人受了伤
伤势如何
I want to know how many
are injured and how bad.
受伤？
Injured?
我们死了4个人！
Four of us are dead!
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
发生在赫伯身上的事，不是谁的错
What happened to herb
is no one's fault.
你说的很对，普雷斯顿
You're absolutely right,
Preston.
我再告诉你一件事情
And I'll tell you
something else.
赫伯没有无谓的死去
Herbert didn't die
for nothing.
他死得其所，我要纪念他
He died for
what he believed in,
and I'm gonna honor that.
他死是因为相信世界上还有些奥秘
He died believing
there was still some mystery
left in this world.
而我们大家
都有可能了解到其中的一部分…
And we could all
have a piece of it...
只消一张门票的价钱
for the price
of an admission ticket.
该死的，普雷斯顿
我们要为赫伯完成这部片子
God damn it, Preston,
we're gonna finish this film
for herb.
我们要完成它…
We'll finish it...
把收益捐给他的妻子和孩子
and donate the proceeds
to his wife and kids.
伙计们，我们还需要更多的绳子
Come on, guys.
We need more rope.
好吧，我们得回去了
All right, we gotta
get back to the ship.
- 安格霍恩会在9小时后开船
- 那又怎样？我们要找到丹劳小姐
Englehorn sails
in nine hours.
So? We gotta find Miss Darrow.
嘿！你在听我讲吗？
我们会被困在这里的
Hey, do you hear me?
We're gonna be
stranded here.
听着，伙计们，丹劳小姐是好姑娘
毫无疑问
Miss Darrow was a great gal,
no question.
她是很好的人
And she was
a wonderful person.
她的死是可怕的损失
我们都会想念她的
It's a terrible loss
and we're all gonna miss her.
我就知道你不是银幕上
所演的那种硬汉形象
I always knew you were
nothing like the tough guy
you play on screen.
我只是没想到你居然是个懦夫
I just never figured you
for a coward.
嘿，伙计，嘿，醒醒吧
Hey, pal! Hey, wake up.
真实生活里的英雄不像我这样
Heroes don't look like me,
not in the real world.
真实生活里他们都有坏牙跟啤酒肚
In the real world,
they got bad teeth,
a bald spot, and a beer gut.
我只是个拿枪的演员
并且失去了动力
I'm just an actor with a gun,
who's lost his motivation.
回头见
Be seeing you.
还有谁吗？
Anyone else?
- 好吧，回见
- 别…
Well, see you.
Come on.
不！
No!
我说了，不！
I said no!
到此为止，没有了
That's all there is.
There isn't any more.
赶他们下船！赶他们下船！
Get them off the boat.
继续划啊！
Keep paddling.
到底是什么东西？
What the hell was that?
来啊，把它们赶跑！
Come on.
Get them out of there!
普雷斯顿！
Preston!
给我你的手
Give me your hand.
杰克！
Jack!
- 老崔！
- 救命！
Choy!
Help!
游啊，你个脏虫子！
Swim, you filthy bugger.
老崔！
Choy!
跟着他
Stay with him.
尽快游到河岸去！
Swim to shore
as fast as you can!
坚持住，普雷斯顿！
Hold on. Preston!
不管发生什么，别丢了摄像机！
Whatever happens,
don't let go of the camera!
别丢了摄像机！
Don't let go
of the camera!
快点，起来，离开水
Come on,
get up out of that water.
起来！
Get up!
来啊，来啊！
Come on, come on.
普雷斯顿，普雷斯顿
Preston. Preston.
还能用
It's working.
你有拍到是吧？
Did you get that, did you?
不！
No!
不
No.
怎么了？
What is it?
赫斯先生？
Mr. Hayes?
如果有什么不测，我希望你赶快跑
If anything happens,
I want you to run.
明白了？
You understand?
我不是懦夫，我才不会跑呢
I'm not a coward.
I ain't gonna run.
这并非什么勇敢，吉米
It's not about
being brave, Jimmy.
回去！
Go back!
回去木桥那边！
Back across the log!
- 我不能就这么跑掉！
- 把吉米带走！
I ain't gonna run!
Get Jimmy out of here!
- 不！
- 后退！后退！
No!
Get back! Get back!
Move back!
- 不！不！
- 呆着别动
No! No!
Stay back.
不！
No!
看着我
Look at me.
- 放他走！
- 你要跑了，吉米
Let him go!
You got to run, Jimmy.
按我说的做
Do as I say.
跟杰克一起走
Go with Jack.
跑啊！
Run!
- 不！
- 开枪射他！
No!
Shoot him!
不！
No!
这里，在这边！
Here! Over here!
坚持住！坚持！
Hold on! Hold on!
兰皮！救我！
Lumpy! Help me!
他妈的地狱，老崔！
Bloody hell, Choy!
不！
No!
哦，我的神啊！
Oh, my!
等等我
Wait!
卡尔
Carl.
吉米！吉米！
Jimmy. Jimmy.
吉米！
Jimmy.
你还好吗？
You all right?
不
No.
下去，下去！
Get off! Get it off!
下去！
Get off!
Get it off!
Get it off! Get it off!
杀了它！
Kill it!
别动
Stop moving!
把它从我脸上弄走
Get it off my face!
- 站着别动
- 我没动
Stay still.
I am standing still.
- 等一下
- 小心！
Hold on.
Be careful!
别动，离崖壁远点
Don't move!
Stay away from the walls!
脱险了！
Coming through!
现在离开那儿！往上爬！
Get out of there now! Climb!
没人能挡我的道
Nobody get in my way.
来吧，吉米，我们走
Come on, Jimmy. Let's go.
爬上绳子，快
Get up the rope.
Let's go. Hurry up.
吉米，我们走了
Jimmy, let's go.
- 快来啊
- 好的
Come on.
Okay.
走
Go.
就在你下沉…
Just as you go down...
到第三也是最后一次时…
for the third
and final time...
就在你的头淹没在浪头下…
as your head disappears
beneath the waves...
你的肺也充满了水…
and your lungs fill
with water...
在你淹死前，你知道那仅存的珍贵的
几秒钟都发生了什么吗？
do you know what happens
in those last precious seconds
before you drown?
来吧，兄弟，爬上绳子去，来啊
离开这，来吧
Come on, buddy.
Get up the rope. Come on.
Get out of here. Come on.
你的整个人生会在眼前一晃而过
Your whole life passes
before your eyes.
而如果你活得像个真正的美国人…
And if you've lived
as a true American...
你会看到那是有色彩的
you get to watch it all
in color.
哦，你会的
Oh, and you will.
现在，你干嘛不爬上绳子呢？快点
Now, why don't you climb
up the rope, huh? Come on.
来吧，德里斯库，我们走
Come on, Driscoll. Let's go.
真美丽
It's beautiful.
美丽
Beautiful.
那边
There.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
别谢上帝，要谢巴克斯特先生
Don't thank God.
Thank Mr. Baxter.
他坚持要救你们
He insisted on
a rescue mission.
我？我就知道你不会有事
Me? I knew you'd be okay.
这就是蟑螂的特点
That's the thing
about cockroaches.
不管你把它们从厕所里冲走多少次…
No matter how many times
you flush them
down the toilet...
它们总是爬回到碗里来
they always crawl
back up the bowl.
嘿，伙计，我从碗里出来了
Hey, buddy?
I'm out of the bowl.
我在晾干我的翅膀
正沿着碗盖散步呢
I'm dryir off my wings
and trekkir across the lid.
德里斯库！
Driscoll!
别犯傻！放弃吧，没用的！
Don't be a fool!
Give it up. It's useless!
她死了
She's dead.
她没死
She's not dead.
杰克会救她回来…
Jack's gonna bring her back...
那猩猩会紧追不放的
and the ape will be
hard on his heels.
我们还有机会翻本，好吧？
We can still
come out of this thing okay.
还有的赚
More than okay.
想想吧
Think about it.
你有一整船的氯仿可用
You got a boat
full of chloroform
we could put to good use.
你想抓那猩猩
You wanna trap the ape?
我可不这么想
I don't think so.
这不是你拿手的吗？活捉动物
Isn't that what you do?
Live animal capture?
我听说你是最好的
I heard you were the best.
杰克！
Jack!
照顾好你自己！
Look after yourself!
把城门开着，可以吗？
Keep the gate open, will you?
没问题，伙计
Sure thing, buddy.
祝你好运！
Good luck!
对不起
I'm sorry.
安
Ann.
杰克！
Jack!
快跑！
Run!
杰克，杰克！
Jack, Jack!
杰克
Jack.
安，没事的
Ann, it's okay.
安，我们走，我们走，来吧！
Ann, let's go.
Let's go. Come on!
我们要走了，来吧
Let's go. Come on.
来啊！
Come on!
卡尔！
Carl!
有人吗，请帮帮我们！
Please! Somebody help us!
他们走了
They've gone.
卡尔，上帝啊！
Carl. Christ.
卡尔！
Carl!
把吊桥放下，现在就放
看在上帝份儿上！
Drop the bridge.
Do it now, for Christ's sake!
还不是时候
Not yet.
等着
Wait.
等着！
Wait!
来啊！
Come on!
就现在！扔钩子啊！
Now!
Throw them!
扔啊！
Throw!
不要！
No!
抓住他
Hold him!
你疯了吗？
Are you out of your mind?
- 住手！
- 抓住绳子
Stop!
Hold the line!
把他压住！
Keep him down!
拉啊！
Heave!
求你了！
Please!
不要！停手！
No! Stop!
杰克
Jack.
- 住手
- 把她带走…
No.
Get her out of...
- 他们会杀了他的！
- 我们什么也做不了
They'll kill him!
There's nothing we can do.
- 不！
- 把她带出它的视线！
No!
Get her out of his sight!
- 太迟了
- 扔啊！
It's too late.
Throw it!
留神啊！
Look out!
放开我
Let go of me.
我们得走了，来吧
We gotta go. Come on.
- 来吧
- 住手
Come on.
Stop it.
放开我！
Leave me alone!
安，求你，走吧
Ann, please come on.
- 打死它！
- 不要！不！
Kill it!
No. No!
结束了，你个疯子
It's over,
you goddamn lunatic!
所有人，逃命！
All of you, run!
加油，加油！
Come on. Come on!
Look out!
跑啊！跑啊！
Move it! Move it!
快，快点！
Come on, come on!
- 待在那！
- 他要的是我！
Stay there!
It's me he wants!
- 求你制止这一起！
- 快走，拦住她！
Please stop this!
Move! Hold onto her!
- 安，走吧
- 求你了，我可以制止他！
Ann, go.
Please, I can stop this!
- 不！
- 安，待在那儿！
No!
Ann, stay there!
离开这儿！
Get it out!
赶快他妈的离开这儿！
Get the hell out of here!
- 来吧！
- 吉米，别犯傻了！来吧
Come on!
Jimmy, don't be crazy!
Come on.
别犯傻了
Don't be crazy.
让我走！
Let me go!
起锚！
Cast off!
来啊，卡尔！
Come on, Carl!
- 划船
- 等等
Row!
Wait.
划船，他妈的！
Row, God damn it!
回去
Go back.
吉米，不！
Jimmy, no!
不！
No!
不！别开枪！放他条生路！
No! Don't! Leave him alone!
躲在后面！
Hide out in the back!
- 等一下！
- 不！
Wait!
No!
不！求你了！不要！
No! No! Please don't!
全世界都会要付钱看它
The whole world
will pay to see this.
我们是百万富翁了，弟兄们！
We're millionaires, boys!
我会跟你们所有人共享的！
I'll share it with all of you!
几个月之内
它的名字会在百老汇的灯光里出现
In a few months
his name will be up
in lights on Broadway!
金刚！世界第八大奇迹！
Kong!
The Eighth Wonder
of the World!
(金刚，世界第八大奇迹）
（金刚，卡尔・丹汉姆的巨型怪兽）
（看安妮・丹劳被奉献给“野兽”）
（售完）
Mr. Denam!
我能说什么？我能说什么？
What can I say?
有什么想法，先生？
Any comments, Mr. Denam?
市长大人，谢谢你
The Mayor, thank you.
准备好
Ready.
我是谁？
What am I?
非常感谢你
Thank you very much.
习惯了就好
Get used to it.
非常高兴见到你，你准备好了吗？
Listen, it's great to see you.
Ready?
谢谢你的关心…
I'm really
appreciating that...
看看你！我记得你
Look at you!
I remember you.
- 你真是好运气，丹汉姆先生
- 可不是好运吗？
You're a lucky guy, Denam.
Am I a lucky guy?
或许你就是个幸运儿
Maybe you're the lucky guy.
卡尔！
Carl!
- 索尔曼！
- 我跟你说了！
Zelman!
I told them.
- 我知道你会来的
- 我真的很喜欢
I know you did
and I appreciate it.
让我们来照相
Let's get a shot of this.
来吧
Come on.
大笑一下
耶！这真是太棒了！
Big smile.
Yeah! That's great!
看看你自己，看看你成了什么样
Look at yourself.
Look at what you've becone.
- 没有女人值得你这样
- 这个女人值得
No woman is won'th this.
This woman is won'th it.
我不管什么代价，一定要赢得她
I don't care what it takes,
I gotta win her back.
哦，真的吗？
Oh, really?
她才不会买这个呢
She's not gonna buy this
for a second.
闭嘴，把那个葡萄柚给我
Shut up and hand me
the grapefruit!
- 你在写一部喜剧？
- 没错
You're writing a conedy?
Yes, I an.
是为你写的
I'n writing it for you.
你为什么要这么做？
Why would you do that?
为什么我要为你写一出戏？
Why would I write
a play for you?
这还不明显吗？
Isn't it obvious?
哦，对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
我无意间听到的
I couldn't help but overhear.
于是，他领我去了那豪华法国餐馆…
So, he took me to this
fancy French restaurant...
吃饭当间，他抓住了我的手
and halfway through
the hors d'oeuvres,
he clutches my hand.
就是他向你表白的时候了吧
他感觉怎样？
And that's when he told you
how he felt?
- 不，他一直没说
- 他一直没说吗？
No. He never said it.
He never said it?
他大概以为不用说了吧
He probably thought
he didn't need to say it.
那她怎么知道这就是认真的呢？
Well, then how does she know
that it's real?
- 他说不必用言语
- 有没有搞错
He said it was
not about the words.
Oh, please!
心里有感动，就说出来
其实很简单的
If you feel it, you say it.
It's really very simple.
他说以后再说，只是，不会有以后了
He said we'd talk
about it later.
Only there was no later.
从来没有说出口过
It never happened.
就这么结束了
That's how it ended.
他让你就这么走了？
他没有试图挽留？
He just let you walk away?
He didn't try to save it?
老实说
我觉得事情或许真的有结果了…
I honestly believed
things might actually
work out...
那就是真的很…
which was really very...
愚蠢
foolish.
男人呐，哦，他会给女人整个世界…
Men.
Oh, they'll give you
the world...
却让最重要的事情…
but they let the one thing
that truly matters...
…溜过指尖
slip through their fingers.
太常见了
Typical.
他们太忙于展示他们的勇敢
以至于忘了用用他们的脑子
They're so busy being brave,
they forget to use
their brains.
浪漫，谁需要？
Romance. Who needs it?
谢谢
Thank you.
女士们，先生们…
Ladies and gentlemen...
我来这里
是要给你们讲述一个奇异的故事
I'm here to tell you
a very strange story.
一个有关我们的历险的故事…
The story of our adventure...
17名探险队员惨死…
in which 17 of our party
suffered horrible deaths...
他们献出了自己的生命…
their lives lost...
去追寻一只野兽…
in pursuit of
a savage beast...
一只大自然创造的狂大怪物
a monstrous aberration
of nature.
但即使是最难对付的畜生
也会被驯服
But even the meanest brute
can be tamed.
是的女士们先生们，你们将要看到…
Yes, ladies and gentlemen,
as you will see...
野兽并不能抵挡…
the beast was no match...
一个女孩的魅力
for the charms of a girl.
一个来自纽约的女孩…
A girl from New York...
她融化了他的心…
Who melted his heart...
这让我们想起古老的阿拉伯诗句…
bringing to mind
that old Arabian proverb...
“看啊，野兽端详着美女的面庞…”
"And lo, the beast looked
upon the face of beauty...
“而美女静立于他的掌中”
"and beauty stayed his hand.
“从那天开始，他便如行尸一般了”
"And from that day forward,
he was as one dead."
现在女士们先生们
我要向你们展示…
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
I'm going to show you...
你们所见过的最伟大的事物
the greatest thing
your eyes have ever beheld.
他是世界之王，他知道
但它在你们面前则是囚犯
He was a king in the world
he knew, but he comes to you
now a captive.
女士们先生们…
Ladies and gentlemen...
我向你们推出
金刚，世界第八奇迹！
I give you Kong,
The Eighth Wonder
of the World!
不必惊惶，这是绝对安全的
Don't be alarmed.
It's perfectly safe.
这些锁链是用铬钢做的！
These chains are made
of chrome steel!
敬请观看…
Observe, if you will...
我手碰到野兽了
I am touching the beast.
我的手放在25英尺高的大猩猩身上
I am actually laying my hand
on the 25-foot gorilla.
伙计们，把它拉起来
Crank 'em up, fellas.
今晚在观众席中…
And now, we have
in the auditorium tonight...
有一位神秘嘉宾
a surprise guest.
故事里的真正英雄
The real-life hero
of this story.
追猎到强大金刚的人！
The man who hunted down
the mighty Kong!
冒着生命危险去解救
身处绝境的女性的人
The man who risked all
to win the freedom
of a helpless female.
为布鲁斯・巴克斯特先生鼓掌
A big hand for
Mr. Bruce Baxter!
谢谢，谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
他说得对
He was right.
关于世界上仍有很多奥秘…
About there still being some
mystery left in this world...
我们大家
都可以了解到其中的一部分…
and we can all have
a piece of it...
只消一张门票的价钱
for the price
of an admission ticket.
你现在了解卡尔了吧
That's the thing you come
to learn about Carl.
他那无穷无尽
破坏他钟爱的事物的能力
His unfailing ability
to destroy the things
he loves.
女士们先生们，请保持镇定…
Please remain calm,
ladies and gentlemen...
现在是这原始的祭祀仪式的高潮
for we now come
to the climax of
this savage ritual.
供奉一位年轻美丽的女孩！
The sacrifice
of a beautiful young girl.
她被献给强大的金刚
Behold her terror as she is
offered up to the mighty Kong!
请为我所见过的
最勇敢的女孩热烈鼓掌！
A big hand, folks,
for the bravest girl
I've ever met!
安・丹劳小姐
Miss Ann Darrow.
把我从野兽手上救出来！
Save me from the beast!
救我！
Help me!
她在哪里？
Where is she?
- 安在哪里？
- 我不知道
Where's Ann?
I have no idea.
我听说他们出一大笔钱
但她干脆地拒绝了
I heard he offered her
all kinds of money
and she turned him down flat.
$ 整理好我所有的烦恼和悲哀
# Pack up all
ny cares and woe #
$ 我来了
# Here I go #
$ 低声吟唱
# singing low #
$ 再见
# Bye bye #
$ 黑鸟
# Blackbird #
$ 是什么地方有个人在等我
# Where sonebody
waits for ne #
$ 糖很甜
# sugar's sweet #
$ 他也一样
# so is he #
$ 再见
# Bye bye #
$ 黑鸟
# Blackbird ##
这就是你们的故事，先生们
here's your story, boys.
“美女和从野兽手里拯救他的男人”
"Beauty and the man
who saved her from the beast."
不
No.
我们赶快把人弄出去
We have to get these people
out of here.
所有人出去了，走吧
Everyone needs to leave, okay?
Come on.
让他吼吧，这镜头很精彩
Let him roar.
It makes a swell picture.
往出口走
Head for the exits.
你自己买座位，伙计，别打我的主意
Get your own seat, buddy.
You're not having mine.
借光，伙计
Excuse me, fellows.
好戏来了，来了，伙计们
Coming through.
Coming through, fellows.
救我下来！救命，求你！
Get me down! Help me, please!
来人啊！来人救救我！
Somebody! Somebody help me!
走！走！出去！
Go! Go! Get out!
走啊！走啊！
Go! Go!
他们在那儿！
There they are.
Come on, come with me.
- 走啊！
- 等等我！
Go!
Wait for me!
回去！
Go back!
走这边！
This way!
救命！
Help!
不！
No!
出租车，跟着那只猩猩
Taxi! Follow that ape.
来吧，老兄，我们要转移他的注意力
Come on, pal,
we gotta draw him off.
这车是你的了，伙计
It's all yours, buddy.
嘿，离开这，女士！
Better get out of here, lady!
来啊
Come on.
伙计！
Buddy!
来啊，来啊！
Come on. Come on.
当心
Look out.
耶稣基督啊
Jesus Christ.
开火！
Fire!
住手！
Stop!
听着
Listen up.
这里是纽约，是神圣的地方
This is New York City,
and this is sacred ground.
你听见我说的了？
You hear me?
这里是人类建造的
也是为人类建造的
It was built for humans,
by humans.
不是给长虱子的臭猩猩建的
Not for stinking
lice-infested apes.
如果一只变种猩猩想…
The thought
of sone nutant gorilla...
踩烂这座美丽城市的每一寸土地
都会令我厌恶
crapping all over the streets
of this fair city,
fills ne with disgust.
所以这就是它的下场
So this is how it's gonna be.
我们找到它，我们就杀了它
We find it. We kill it.
砍掉它丑陋的头颅，砸碎它…
We cut its ugly head off
and we ram it up...
不，不
No. No.
真美丽
Beautiful.
是的
Yes.
是的，很美
Yes, it is.
Look at that.
嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey!
禁止通行
Nobody past this point.
你不能进去！
You can't go in there!
嘿！
Hey!
抓住他！
Stop him!
嘿！回来！你不能进来！
Hey! Get back.
You're not allowed up there!
- 怎么回事？
- 快走！
What's going on?
Go!
不！
No!
求你！不！
Please! No!
不！
No!
安，安
Ann. Ann.
走开
Move along.
就拍一下，拍一下！
Just one shot! One shot!
- 过来，过来！
- 伙计们，照张相怎么样？
Come, come!
Boys, how about a photo?
看着我
Look at me.
来吧，看着相机
Come on, watch the camera.
站得再近一点
Come a little closer.
好了，伙计们，完事了，退后
That's it, folks.
Show's over. Step back!
清理现场，就这样，退后，兄弟们
Clear the area. That's it.
Shove off, boys.
为什么它要那样？
Why'd he do that?
爬那么高，把自己困住了
Climb up there
and get himself cornered.
猩猩肯定知道是什么下场
The ape must have known
what was coming.
它就是个蠢动物，啥都不懂
He's just a dumb animal.
Didrt know nothing.
它算个麻烦吗？飞机收拾了它
What does it matter?
Airplanes got him.
不是飞机
It wasrt the airplanes.
是美女杀死了野兽
It was beauty
killed the beast.
Sokidon Proudly Presents